Joe Pham

Toronto, Ontario, Canada



ptlam.vn95@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ptlam95

Summary

I am a detail-oriented aspiring iOS App Developer, lifelong learner, and former Hospitality / Customer Service professional with 4-years experience. I enjoy app development because of the satisfaction drawn from overcoming challenges. I'm motivated by the positive impact that software could bring to change the life of individuals, and the whole as a whole, for the better.

I do my best to advance and equip myself each day with new knowledge of the field, especially in iOS/Swift application development, and transform them into real life projects.

Skills & Technologies:

Swift | Xcode | UIKit | Networking | JSON Parsing | Auto Layout | Git | GitHub | Python | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | C# | Bash/Shell scripting | Object-Oriented Programming | MySQL

Experience



Fulltime Student

George Brown College

Sep 2020 - Present (7 months +)

- Studying a 3-year Advanced Diploma in Computer Programming and Analysis.
- · Assisted fellow students overcome academic challenges with live demo tutorials.
- Elevated teamwork efficiency with interpersonal and technical skills



iOS App Developer

Self-learner

Dec 2020 - Present (4 months +)

- Learning iOS Development with Swift (and SwiftUI in the near future) on my own, outside of college's curriculum.
- · Boosting my programming knowledge furthermore by coding, self-extending, and bug-fixing real world iOS app projects along the self educational path.

Guest Service Agent

InterContinental Nha Trang

Apr 2016 - Jul 2019 (3 years 4 months)

- Exhibited highest customer service with coordinated regular communication among departments.
- Delivered memorable customer experience with being an active listener, empathetic expressions, personal interactions, awarded with "Employee of the Month" title.
- Implemented efficient organizing skills to increase productivity and minimize work tasks by 50% of time.

• Utilized multilingual ability to aid various hotel guests' needs; 1.5-year experience in merchandising upselling.

Education

George Brown College

Advanced Diploma, Computer Programming 2020 - 2023

Federation University Australia

Bachelor's Degree, Hospitality Administration/Management 2012 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

- Bachelor Degree of Hospitality Federation University Australia
- in Listening to Customers LinkedIn
- Selling into Industries: Retail and Consumer Products LinkedIn
- Customer Service: Creating Customer Value LinkedIn
- Introduction to Packet Tracer Cisco

Honors & Awards

Golden Key Honour Society Alumni - Golden Key International Honour Society
Feb 2015

Golden Key recognizes high-achieving students for their commitment to academics—undergraduates for being in the top 15% of their class, and top-performing graduate students.

Employee of the Month - InterContinental Nha Trang Hotel

Nov 2018

Recognition by top management board for excellent customer service and dedicated contribution to teamwork of Front Office department at InterContinental Nha Trang Hotel

Dean's Honour List - Centre of Information Technology, George Brown College Feb 2021

Recognized for Academic Success (overall GPA of 4.0) of the Winter 2021 semester at George Brown College, Toronto, ON, Canada.